我不打算从
I'm not to start with
说说我是如何在OK源中做出贡献的故事
a story of how I got into contributing in ok source
所以在2020年的时候
so back in 2020
我得到了我的第一个Futangian PSA front m wbp opera
I got my first futangian PSA front m wbp opera
但当时我有一个问题
but at the time I have an issue
在那里我试图找到
where I'm trying to find
技术来学习
technologies to learn
但我总是
but I always
没有时间把它放在副业上
don't have the time to put it in the side projects
所以我在想
so I was thinking
什么东西可以更省力
what could be less effort
但又能得到同样的游戏回报
but have thissame game in return
因此，当我走进开放源码项目的时候
so that's when I walk into open source projects and
我贡献的第一个项目是V Pluginso Belt
the first one I contribute to is v pluginso belt
它是一个
which is a
的插件。
plugin from v
和
and
我很喜欢它，我在世界和一个表格中使用它。
I quite like it I use it at world and a form
但后来我做了一个修正
but then I made a fix
然后
and then
我发现的是，fick
what I find is that fick
我可以为每个使用该软件包的人做出贡献
I may contribute to everyone who's using the package
和
and
我觉得有一种
I kind of feel a
很好的了解了这一点
great knowing about that
从那以后，我就一直在做开源的工作。
and from there on I've been working on open sources so
今天的主题可以是贡献一个或一个
the topic for today can be contributing one or one
其中
which
我已经有了
I've got
味道和技巧以及你需要知道的一切
taste and tricks and everything you need to know
关于在开源世界中的贡献
about contributing in the world of open source
关于我，我是来自马来西亚的Brdu。
so a little bit about me I'm brdu and from Malaysia
我目前是feed和sabel的核心团队成员。
I am currently a core team member on feed and sabel
我也是Astro的一个核心成员。
I'm also a core resident in astro
我一直在与
I've been doubling with
我已经和open swords合作了2年了
open swords for about 2 years right now
而且
and
我也学会了自然，可以花几个小时
I also learned nature could spend like hours
观察天空什么的
watching sky or something
但没有进一步的废话
but without further ado
跳到
jump next to
主要观点
the main point
这就是开放源码
which is open source
所以你可能会注意到任何一个开放源码社区
so you may notice any open source community
我们都有这个缩写，叫做OSS
we have this acronym called oss
那么什么是OSS呢？
so what is oss
OSS是开放源码软件的缩写
oss stands for open source software
就是你可以直接阅读的软件
which is software that you can read
直接阅读源代码
the source code directly
来了解它是如何工作的
to understand how it works
而且很多时候
and often times
时，该软件还与一种叫做
when the software is also related to something called
foss，也就是免费的f星。
foss which is f that stars for free
所以自由和开放的软件
so free and open software
它说你读了一个kps
it says you read a kps
开放源码总是容易传播
open source always easily distributed
免费的
free
但有时你也可以看到付费软件
but sometimes you can see paid software as well
比如说
for example
付费许可证或商业许可证
paid licenses or commercial licenses
但你可以清楚地注意到一个问题
but you could clear notice a problem
如果它是免费的，或者说它是自己维持的
if it's free or does it sustain itself
所以这是个大问题
so this is a big deal
有时你会注意到像
and sometimes you notice like
一个问题，得到在起床
an issue that gets on get up
有人问是否需要维护项目
where someone's asking if projects to maintain
有时这是真的
sometimes it's true
因为该项目工作得很好，就像这样
because the project is working fine as this
而且没有
and there isn't
任何需要维护的东西
anything that needs to be maintained
因此，它是完全正确的
so that it's perfectly fine
但有时它实际上是被放弃了
but sometimes it actually is abandoned
因为项目的维护者
because the project maintainers
没有足够的资源来继续进行这个项目
doesn't have the resources to continue on the project
而被遗弃，就像这样
and is left as this
这也是一个问题
and this is also an issue
这也是一个在开源领域经常出现的问题。
that comes up often in the or of open source
因此，我们如何帮助，所以从
so how do we help so from
我目前的经验是
my experience touch far is that
从我的经验来看，我们可以帮助的事情基本上是有的。
there is basically treat things that we could help
所以可以这样说
so the way to
总结一下，就是
summarize it is that
与代码
with code
社区和资金
community and funding
所以在这个演讲中，我想深入探讨这3点
so in this talk I like to deep dive into these
3点，并提供信息，说明你如何能够
3 points and provide information on how you could
在这些领域工作并为之做出贡献
work in this areas and contribute to them
因此，贡献代码
so contributing code
在他们的项目中，我们做的第一件事将是
the first thing we do in their project will be
制作报告
making about reports
所以，如果你发现了一个问题，你就会创建有关报告
so if you find an issue you create about report
但需要注意的是
but something important to notice is that
确保这实际上是
making sure that is actually
以上
above
有时你可能只有一个问题
sometimes you may only have a question
或者你不确定你是否在做这件事
or you're uncertain if you're doing it
正确的方式
the right way
有时它实际上是一个配置问题，即
sometimes it is actually a configuration issue where
在你的项目中你没有
in your project you are not
正确使用该项目
using the project correctly
所以
so
知道它是否在上面，可以节省大量的时间
knowing if it's above or not saves a lot of time
而且在这一点上
and in that
在这一点上，你也要遵循模板，所以每个
point you will also want follow the template so each
储存库可能会或可能不会尝试
repositories may or may not have attempted
时都会尝试。
when falling an issue
如果他们这样做，对所有的问题都很重要
if they do its important for all the issues
和
and
达到通过他们和下降的指示，以
reach through them and fall instructions to
的结果
the result
将创造一个最小的复制
will create a minimum reproduction
但有时对维护者来说，重要的是
but sometimes it is important for maintainers to
容易重现的问题，这样他们就可以很容易地解决它。
easily reproduce issues so that they can easily hit it
迅速做出修复，而不是
make fix quickly instead of
让每个人
having everyone
手动实现你自己的中心
manually implementing your own center
因此，这是功能和代码
so this is functional and code
但是，从这里得到的主要收获是
but the main takeaway from this is that
它为贡献者节省了时间
it save times for contributors
不仅仅是维护者，还有
not only to maintainers but
任何有兴趣帮助这个项目的人
anyone who is interested in helping in the project
也将受益于
will also benefit from
如果你遵循
if you follow
这些指南
these guides
但这些网站正在创建酒吧报告
but the sites are creating bar reports
还有一些你可以做的事情，那就是
there's something else you can do which is
直接进行自我修复
directly making to fix yourself
因此，当你开始进行修复时
so when you start making a fix
它可能是
it could be
在一个小项目中，或者在一个大项目中
on a small project or can be in a big project
或小项目，你可能需要
or small project you may take
30分钟或一个多小时
30 minutes or an hour plus
来
to
消化所有东西并进行修复
digest everything and make the fix
但有时在一个大项目中，这可能是困难的
but sometimes in a big project it could be hard
这也是可以理解的
which is understandable
时至今日，我还没有真正
to this day I don't really
我不太了解警察的一切
understand everything in a v cop base
但这并不重要
but that is fine
开始的简单方法是阅读
and an easy way to start off is to read
贡献指南
the contributing guide
你应该有
you should have
所有你需要的信息
all the information you need
在本地设置该项目
to set up the project locally
测试它和
to test it and
来进行你所遇到的修改，以及在哪里可以找到它。
to make changes that you meet and where to find it and
我还发现从修复about开始是最容易的。
I've also found it easiest to start with fixing about
因为about通常触及一个非常具体的领域
since about usually touches a very specific domain
所以你只需要修复
so you only have to fix
也许是一个特定的文件，也许只是一个目录
maybe a specific file or maybe just a directory
所以你不需要阅读整个
so you don't have to read the entire
拷贝来进行自己的修复
copies to make your own fix
而仅仅是某一小段代码
but onlya certain small piece of code
通常这就足以让你获得
and usually this is enough for you to gain
获得关于该因素的上下文软
gain context on the factor soft
并发送一个PR或完整的请求
and send a PR or full request
但有时，如果你不能遵循
but sometimes if you can't follow
事实上
indeed
我们在这个法庭上有一个贡献渠道，其中
we have a contributing channel in this court where
所有的贡献者
all the contributors
包括核心维护者都在那里提供帮助
including the core maintainers are there to help
和
and
但同样重要的是要理解，有时
but it's also important to understand that sometimes
人们很忙，而且
people are busy and
他们可能不会很快完全得到一些
they may not get entirely few soon
所以你可能要自己去摸索
soyou may have to feel things on yourself
但我认为
but I think
最终这导致了最后的一点，即
ultimately this leads to the final point where
这
this
一个自我学习的经验，其中
a self learning experience where
你在这个世界上更加独立。
you're more independent on your own in the world
开放源代码
open source
但你也会在一天结束时
but you also at the end of day
为维护者节省时间，因为
save time for maintainers since
因为从长远来看，你是在帮他们的忙。
you're doing them a favor in the long run
你可以做的另一件事是
another thing you could do is
通过对报告征收三倍的费用
by triharging about reports
所以在右边的图片上
so on the image on the right
你可以看到，有一堆的问题
you could see that there is a bunch of issues
哪些是没有
which is not
还没有被查看
being viewed yet
而这是一个
and this is a
开源项目的常见问题是
common problem in being open source projects is that
有这么多的问题，但却没有那么多的
there are so many problems but there's so little
时间去了解
time to understand
这究竟是一个问题
is that actually a problem
还是它已经被固定为一个陷阱
or it's already fixed as a trap
这有点像回到了第一点，即
which kind of brings back to point number one where
你应该
you should
了解它在哪里
understand where it's above
或不
or not
但如果你对树的问题感兴趣的话
but if you're interested in tree are doing issues
这是一个非常有帮助的事情
which is a very helpful thing to do
因为他们作为防御的第一个迹象
because they act as the first signs of defense
在
before
问题到达维护者手中之前的第一道防线
the issue reached to the hands on the maintainers
因为有时一个问题是
because sometimes an issue is
无效的
invalid
或选择或复制
or elects or reproduction
在我们深入研究之前，这些问题可能很容易被撇开。
these could be easy to skim off before we dive deeper
到它
into it
而且
and
通过所有这些问题也有助于
going through all these issues also helps
了解教育工作者
understand educators
有时你会发现一个非常具体的问题
sometimes you find a very specific issue
或5个或更多的问题
or 5 or more issues
彼此之间有某种联系
that are kind of related to each other
这样你就有了关于具体问题的背景
so you have like context on specific issues
在那里你可以解决
where you can fix
而不是只解决一个非常具体的问题。
in a holistic way instead of fixing just
一个非常具体的事情
one very specific thing
还有
and also
对问题进行分类有助于你
triagging issues helps you
了解决策背后的背景
understand the context behind decisions
例如，如果维护者决定
for example if maintainers decide to
拒绝一项提议
reject a proposal
或拒绝
or reject
也许是因为它是故意的
about maybe because it's intentional
或者说这是个很好的理由
or maybe that's like a very good reason
它是出于对其产品的嘲弄
it is out of scoop of its product
所以知道如何添加
so knowing how to add
在某些情况下，这样做是非常有帮助的
in certain cases like this is very helpful
因为你可以想
because you could think
维护者的思维方式，这
the way maintainers think and that
有助于释放一些
helps to release some
他们所承担的责任
responsibilities that they have
当然
and of course
这个选项需要在项目中体验
this option needs to experience in a project
方向和他们在整个项目中的理念。
direction and their philosophy in the whole
和另一件事来做和
and another thing to do and
对代码的贡献是审查代码的变化
contributing to code is reviewing code changes
所以基本上当
so basically when
在项目中，你可能有完整的请求
in the project you might have full request
与一堆的变化
with a bunch of changes
审查代码需要时间
reviewing tr takes time stupiers
你需要确保
you need to make sure that
什么变化是正确的
what change is correct
而且它不会
and it doesn't
破坏其他东西
break anything else
所以如果你是审查PRS的新手
so if you're new to reviewing prs
从小事做起是个好地方
starting small is a good place to start
或例子
or example
微观变化文件
micro changes documentation
或
or
小的修复，谁
small fixes who
是非常具体的
are very specific
较大的外套，容易消化
larger in the coat which is easily digestible
但也
but also
提出意见也会给你带来很大的帮助
making comments also brings you to a long way
只是对你可能发现的具体问题进行评论
just making comments on specific issues you may find
例如，尝试在当地测试PRS，你会发现
for example try to test prs locally and you find
问题，也可能没有
problems or maybe not
但这表明你把
but this shows that you put
努力去审查PRS
effort into reviewing prs
所以发表评论会让它对维护者来说更可信。
so making comments kind of makes it more credible to
维护者
the maintainers
知道你确实付出了努力
knowing that you actually put effort into it
除非
unless
这也是上一点的内容，即
this also counts up to the previous point which is
学习接触
learning the contact
决策者背后的联系，而维护者可能
behind the decisions that maintainers may
有时你会遇到维护者拒绝修改的情况
sometimes you have changes that maintainers reject
或者是他们要求
or maybe they request
对其进行特定的焦化修改
specific coke changes to it
这可以帮助你了解你的项目所使用的特定模式
this helps you understand specific patterns that
你的项目使用的具体模式
your project uses
再往前走，你就开始
further along you start
了解你应该遵循的具体模式
understanding specific patterns that you should follow
而且你可以对它进行Venus处理
and you can Venus along to it
当你开始审查PRS时也是如此
and when you start reviewing prs as well
并最终
and ultimately
从以前的观点来看
from the previous points
你实际上是在应用你的经验
you are actually applying your experience
查看你的PRS时
when view your prs
因此，从分流问题到制造问题或
so from triaging issues making issues or
只是做一个修复
just making a fix
这些都有助于最终审查PRS
these are all helpful in ultimately reviewing the prs
编写的代码，这些代码将进入
that is code that's going into
主项目的代码
the main project
所以要总结一下
so to kind of summarize the
贡献的观点
contribution point of view
你可以看到，在很长一段时间内
you can kind of see that for a long
责任开始上升
responsibility start to rise
所以
so
这或多或少像是一个光谱，当你成为
this is more or less like a spectrum when you become
贡献者到指导者
a contributor to a mentator
所以你的责任越大，你就越
so the more responsible you can get the more
你就越重要
important you are
但在下一个问题上，我们有一个社区
but on the next point we have the community
所以
so
社区也是另一个非常
community is also another very
在一个项目中非常重要的方面
important aspect in a project
如果没有社区的存在
without a community there
该项目基本上是
the project is basically
没有人使用它
no one uses it
所以
so
第一件重要的事情是提出正确的问题
the first important thing is asking the right questions
所以当你
so when you
时，你不会真的只是
go in and comedy you don't really just
去github或者随便去哪里
go on github or just go anywhere
重要的是要知道在哪里，因为
it is important to know where as that
你应该提出问题
you are supposed to ask questions
以及你应该提供的信息
and also the information that you should give
有时
sometimes
你给它太长了
you give it too long
太过口头化
it's too verbals
人们并不真的喜欢
people don't really feel like
检查它，因为
checking it because
因为这就像一篇文章，我花了很多精力去了解一个问题
it's like an essay and I've put a lot of effort to
了解一个问题
understand a question
但要尽量短小精悍，以提供
but try to be short andconcise got to give
所有需要的信息
all the information needed
以便有人能读一遍
so that someone can read it once
他们就可以回答一次
and they can answer it once
这样就能节省双方的时间
so it saves time in both parties
保持一个简短的房子，以
of keeping a short house done to
减少连接性的流程
reduce a connective flow
当他们试图了解你的问题是什么
when they try to understand what your problem is
还有
and also
信号尽量不要在
signal try not to spam in
渠道
the channels
有时
and sometimes
不是每个人都有时间来
not everyone has a time to
检查你的问题或你的问题
check out your problem or your question
这很重要
it's important
请随时支付
feel free to always pay
再来一次，比如在几个小时后，这样
again like in a couple of hours so that
每个人都有机会
everyone has a chance to
在时机成熟的时候再重新审视这个问题
revisit that again when the time comes
在你提出问题的时候
and while you're asking out questions
和有用的提示
and helpful tip
那么我有
then I had
在过去，尽量在同一时间回答他们的问题
in the past as try to answer them at the same time
所以
so
在你问问题之前，你可以
before you ask questions you can
看看是否有其他人有问题
thearound see if anyone else have problems
你可以试着回答他们
you can try to answer them
如果你能做到最好
the best if you can
并提供想法，即使你不确定如何解决它
and give ideas even if you're not sure how to fix it
这也是一个很好的方法，可以
and that is a great way to
邀请别人来回答你的问题
invite others to answer your question as well
这就像一个双向的街头服饰
this is like a 2 way streetwear
每个人都在互相帮助
everyone is helping each other
和其他任何一天
and any other day
一些问题实际上是一个问题的房间，其中
something questions actually room to a problem where
文件是一个问题
documentation is a problem
需要澄清的问题
needs to be clarified
和所有这些导致
and all these leads to
了解痛点或项目
understanding the pain points or the project
因此，这是一个非常重要的事情，其中
so this is a very important thing where
用户自己的项目不比维护者多
the users auto project no more than the maintainers
因此，对于打
so for beat
这里有一些链接，击败用户或支持
here are like a few links that beat users or support
你可以打电话给聊天VHS com死亡，这是
you can call chat VHS com death which is
一个链接，我们可以看到迪斯科的帮助
a link to discord we can see for help
或者我们也可以询问和
or we can also ask and
可以在VHS中讨论，在我们的repo中讨论。
can have discussion in theVHS in our repo
你也可以查看VHS在开发中的文档
you can also check out the documentation at VHS on dev
和
and
文档
the documentation
也可以在VHS repo中进行修改。
changes could also be made on the VHS repo
因此，下一个问题将是资金
and so the next one will be funding
所以资金也是另一个重要方面
so funding is also another important aspect
即使你只是为它提供资金
even if you're only contributing money to it
是
is
对任何项目来说，要维持你的主题，就必须要有战斗力
fighter for any project to sustain your subject
春天的层级总是花自己的空闲时间
spring tiers are always spending their own free time
工作，所以
working on it so
一种方法是使用赞助
one way is to use sponsorship
以每月或一次性的方式来赞助他们
to sponsor them on a monthly basis or one time basis
这包括得到一半的赞助商或PATREON
this includes a get half sponsors or patreon
除此之外，一些公司还提供
and besides that some companies also offer
资助的百分比，这样的话，你就可以在世界范围内进行开源。
a percentage of the world walking open source so that
例如，你可以工作
for example you can work
70%在主公司的工作上
70 percent on the maincompany work
和30
and 30
开源的
open source one
在一天结束的时候
at the end of day
这对双方都有好处，因为
a benefits both sides where
公司可能
the company may
需要开放源码的专业知识
need the expertise of the open source
项目来工作
project to work
在主要公司中也是如此
on the main company as well
但这也是另一条双向的道路
but this is also another 2 way street
帮助每个人
where helps everyone
同时也是一种普遍的服务工作
and also sound the universal work of services
这有点像赞助
which is kind of like sponsorship
但你会得到一些回报
but you get something in return
比如说你需要维护者的支持，你可以得到
say you need support from the maintainers you can get
直接帮助他们
direct help on them
这也是支持这些项目的另一种方式
which is also another way to support these project
维护者的最终媒体
maintainers the ultimate media
你在笔上使用的项目也得到了维护
project that you use on the pen is also maintained
这也有助于你使用的产品
which also helps with the product that you used
构建在它上面的产品
to build on top of it
所以它也会帮助你获得回报
so it will help you in a return as well
总结一下上面的内容
to kinda summarize the top
这是我做的一个方便的清单
here's a handy list that I've made
汇编了我们目前所做的每一项工作的要点
compiling every points that we have tasked far
但你可以在未来再次使用参考
but you can use to reference in the future again
最重要的是要有乐趣
and most importantly have fun
项目工作
work on projects
你是否有兴趣把它作为一种心态来做？
are you interested in making it as a heartbeat
不要试图把自己逼得太紧
don't try to push yourself too much
在需要的时候休息一下
and take breaks where needed
不要倦怠，也不要
don't burn out and also
尊重他人，他们也在努力
be respectful to others who are also trying
贡献的人
to contribute to
资源的人。
the resource as well
这就是我的全部想法
and that is all for my thought
谢谢你的聆听
thank you for listening
我可以特别感谢在他们的旅程中帮助我的主宰者
and I can give special thanks to the dominating
我可以特别感谢那些在他们的旅程中帮助我的epita和
epita who helped me in their journey and
位的来源，如果没有他们的健康，我
bit source where I've
没有他们的健康，我永远不会有今天的成就
never been where I am today without their health
你可以在我的社交网站上找我
and you could look for me on my socials
在github上，也就是bluey，或者在twitter上的blueview。
on github which is bluey or on twitter blueview